(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-09-27T22:47:05.919439",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
そこに膝をつけ！
Get down on your knees!
吐いて捨てるような現実は
A reality you'd spit on and throw away...
一刀両断 叩き斬る！
...I'll slice through in a single stroke!
終わりのない輪廻に迷いし子らよ
Oh children lost in an endless cycle of reincarnation,
漆黒の翼で誘おう
I shall guide you with pitch-black wings.
我ら、エデンの星を統べる者！
We are the rulers of Planet Eden!
秘密結社
Secret Society...
holoX！
...holoX!
でござる！
...de gozaru!
Woah oh, woah oh oh oh oh oh
How low? どうしようもないこの世界
How low? In this hopeless world,
どうしてほしい？
what do you want us to do?
Black out 終末告げる鐘が鳴る
Black out, the bell tolling the end rings out.
ラッパッパッパッパラッパ 手取ろぜ
Rappappappapparappa, take my hand,
チートしようぜ 陰キャも陽キャも
let's use cheats, introverts and extroverts alike!
Sing a song 気持ちいいことだけが全て
Sing a song, feeling good is all that matters.
堕ちてゆく 闇の底へ
Falling down to the bottom of darkness.
M-A-I-M-A-I Melody
ほらどうぞどうぞ 手の鳴る方へ
come on, right this way, towards the clapping hands.
もう逃げられない
There's no escaping anymore.
ほら 闇に染まれば
See, once you're dyed in darkness...
世界を塗り替えろ
...repaint the world!
望めばくれてやろう すべて
If you desire it, we'll give you everything!
常識破り捨てろ
Tear away and discard common sense!
狂狂狂狂 狂乱の正義を告げろ
Proclaim the justice of sheer madness!
ラッパッ パーラッパッ
Rappap pa-rappap!
すべてを喰らい尽くせ
Devour everything completely!
ラッパッ パーラッパッ
Rappap pa-rappap!
秘密を教えてやろう
I'll let you in on the secret.
Woah oh, woah oh oh oh oh oh
悪のカリスマ 導く ユートピックさ
An evil charisma leads us—it's utopic!
正義とか知らない 意志を鳴らして 誘い
Knowing nothing of justice, sounding our will and tempting you.
真面目に不真面目 狂乱の宴で
Seriously unserious at this banquet of frenzy,
望み求め 願い叶え 世界征服？
seeking desires, granting wishes, world domination?
ラッパッパって手取ろぜ Swingしようぜ
Rappappa, take my hand and let's swing!
退屈な世界へ バイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye to the boring world!
覚めることのない 夢を見せる
I'll show you a dream from which you'll never wake.
ほら お眠りなさい
Come now, go to sleep.
もっともっと遠くへ
Farther and farther away...
ほらどうぞどうぞ 行きたいんでしょう？
Come on, right this way, you want to go, don't you?
もうやめられない
You can't stop anymore.
ほら 悪に染まれば
See, once you're steeped in evil...
世界を塗り替えろ
...repaint the world!
望むもの与えよう すべて
We'll give you everything you desire!
ルールを書き換えろ
Rewrite all the rules!
狂狂狂 回し尽くせ 焼き尽くす
Spin and spin around completely, burning it all down!
ラッパッ パーラッパッ
Rappap pa-rappap!
すべてのはみ出し者へ
To all the misfits out there!
ラッパッ パーラッパッ
Rappap pa-rappap!
秘密を教えてやろう
I'll let you in on the secret.
時は熟した！
The time is ripe!
狂気の宴の始まりだ！
The banquet of madness has begun!
貴様ら！
You bastards!
準備はいいかー！
Are you ready?!
刮目せよ！
Pay close attention!
クロエ！
Chloe!
手あげな！
Put your hands up!
いろは！いろは！叫ぶでござる！
Iroha! Iroha! Let's shout, de gozaru!
こより！こより！踊っせ！踊っせ！
Koyori! Koyori! Let's dance! Let's dance!
世界を手にするholoX！世界を変えてくholoX！
holoX taking over the world! holoX changing the world!
ルイ姉！ルイ姉！待った？待った？
Lui-nee! Lui-nee! Did you wait? Did you wait?
ラプラス！ラプラス！最後は全員行くぞ！
Laplus! Laplus! Everyone together at the end, let's go!
holoX！holoX！
holoX! holoX!
世界を手にするholoX！
holoX taking over the world!
世界を変えてくholoX！
holoX changing the world!
世界をこの手にholoX！
holoX holding the world in our hands!
心を解き放て
Unleash your heart.
ほらどうぞ 望みをお任せて
Come on, entrust your wishes to us.
もう逃げられない
You can no longer run away.
ほら 闇に染まれば
Look, once you're dyed in darkness...
世界を塗り変えろ
...repaint the world!
望めばくれてやろう 全て
If you wish for it, I'll give it all to you.
常識投げ捨てろ
Throw away common sense.
狂狂狂い倒せ 火をつけろ
Go crazy, crazy, utterly crazy, light the fire!
ラッパッパッパラッパ
Ra-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
全てを奪いつくせ
Snatch everything away!
ラッパッパッパラッパ
Ra-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
秘密を教えてやろう
I'll let you in on the secret.
Woah-oh, woah-oh-oh-oh-oh
提供 "カバー株式会社"
[Sponsor: COVER Corporation]
この配信は、ご覧のスポンサーの提供でお送りします
This stream is brought to you by the following sponsor.
えー、皆さん、本日は、
Uhm, everyone, today,
holoXの2周年を祝う記念配信におや、おれ...
for this stream celebrating holoX's 2nd anniversary—wait, huh...
お集まりいただき、ありがとうございます。
thank you very much for gathering here.
我々は...
We are...
くっ
Kh...
我々holoXは、2周年を迎えましたが、
We, holoX, have reached our 2nd anniversary,
これまでっ...
and up until n—
これまでと変わらず、
just as before—
否！
no!
これまで以上に世界征服のために
even more than before, for the sake of world conquest,
活動していくことを、ここで改めて宣言させていただきます。
we hereby declare once again that we will carry on our activities.
そして、
And,
吾輩のお名前は、ラプラス・ダークネスです。
my name is La+ Darknesss.
えー、3年目の抱負は...
Uhm, as for my resolution for the 3rd year...
頑張ります。
I will do my best.
では、2周年の抱負と、
Now then, as for 2nd anniversary resolutions
自己紹介を鷹嶺ルイから、
and self-introductions, starting with Takane Lui,
順番に一言ずついただきたいと思います。お願いします。
I'd like each of you to say a few words in turn. Please go ahead.
はい。holoXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します。
Yes. I am holoX's executive officer, Takane Lui.
えー、3年目の抱負は、歌を頑張るのと、
Uhm, my resolutions for the 3rd year are to work hard on singing, and...
えー、鷹嶺の「鷹」の字を間違えられずに、
...uhm, having people post without misspelling...
えー、ポストしてもらうことを目標に頑張りたいと思います。よろしくお願いいたします。
...the kanji for "Taka" in Takane—that's my goal. Pleased to make your acquaintance.
はい！holoXの頭脳、博衣こよりです！
Yes! I'm holoX's brain, Hakui Koyori!
3年目、えー、
For year three... um,
この2年目は2000時間配信していたらしいです。
apparently I streamed for 2,000 hours in this 2nd year.
だが、しかし！もっと配信だけじゃなく、歌やダンスなど、
However! Not just streaming more, but also singing, dancing,
夢のソロライブに向かって見てもらっていきたい！
and heading toward my dream solo live, I want everyone to watch me!
全て欲張って頑張っていきたいと思います！よろしくお願いします！
I want to greedily go after everything and do my best! Thank you very much!
はい！holoXのインターン、沙花叉クロヱです！
Yes! I'm holoX's intern, Sakamata Chloe!
今年、あ、3年目の抱負は、
This year... ah, for my 3rd year resolution,
もうちょっと勝ちたいです。よろしくお願いします。
I want to win a bit more. Thank you very much.
ん？あ、ギャンブル？
Hm? Ah, gambling?
はい。次こそ勝ちます。
Yes. I'll win next time for sure.
公に言ったの...
Saying that in public...
はい！holoXの用心棒、風真いろはでござる！
Yes! I'm holoX's bodyguard, Kazama Iroha, de gozaru!
3年目の抱負は、今年はいっぱいオリジナルの楽曲を作りたいなっていうのと、
My 3rd year resolution: I want to make lots of original songs this year, and...
今年こそ正社員になって給料を上げてもらうことです！よろしくお願いします！
...this year, become a full-time employee and get a salary raise! Thank you!
無理ですね。
That's impossible.
えー、さてさて、我々holoXは、2周年を機に、
Uhm, now then, on the occasion of our 2nd anniversary,
あるビッグプロジェクトを始動させていこうかと考えております。
we, holoX, are planning to launch a certain big project.
はい。この度holoXは、
Yes. This time, holoX...
人々に愛される世界征服を目標に掲げ、
...aiming for world conquest that is loved by the people,
大型テーマパークをオープンすることになりました。
...will be opening a large-scale theme park.
それがこちらになります。
And here it is.
バーチャル“エデン” holoXランド
[Virtual "Eden" holoX Land]
バーチャル“エデン” holoXランド！
Virtual "Eden" holoX Land!
開園は、来年中を予定しておりますが、
The opening is scheduled for sometime next year,
本日は、ゲストの方々をご紹介いたしまして、一部...
but today, we have invited some guests to show part of...
アトラクションを先行体験いただこうと思っております
We'd like to have you experience the attractions in advance.
というわけで、ここからはホロックスランドの...
And so, from here on, we will bring you...
プレオープンの模様をお届けしていきまーす！
...scenes from the pre-opening of holoX Land!
アトラクションの体験会が終わったら、holoXのライブも開催します。
Once the attraction preview is over, we will also hold a holoX live concert.
これからも、どうか...
From now on, please...
あ、こちらも、皆さんどうかお見逃しなく。
Ah, please don't miss this one either, everyone!
噛みすぎですね。
You stumbled so much.
じゃ、みんな行くぞー！
Alright, let's go, everyone!
あれー？ここら辺だと思うんだけどなー
Huh? I think it was around here...
待って、なんか...変な、なんか装置あるんですけど...
Wait, there's some... strange device here...
ここでいいのかなー？あれ？
Is this the right place? Huh?
でも誰もいねえんだけど！
There's nobody here, though!
あれ、呼ばれた気がしたんだけど！
Huh? I thought I heard someone call!
あれ？なんか変な会見してた人...
Huh? The people who were having that weird press conference...
変な会見って言われた！
She called it a weird press conference!
いや、どうもどうもどうもー。ちょっとお待たせいたしましたー。
Well, hello, hello! Sorry to have kept you waiting.
お邪魔しますー
Pardon the intrusion~
いらっしゃいませー！
Welcome!
すいませんねー、ホントにねー
Thank you so much, really.
ちなみに団長、なんかアトラクションが遊べるみたいな感じで来て...
By the way, Danchou was told that I could try out some attractions and came, but...
いいんですか、ここで？アトラクションってこのよく分かんない椅子のやつだったり...
Is it okay here? By attraction, do you mean this weird chair contraption...?
これでございます！
This is it!
はい。こちらは観覧車にクイズのゲーム性、
Yes. This is a new sensory attraction combining a Ferris wheel, quiz games,
絶叫マシンのスリルを追加した新感覚アトラクション、「ホイールシューターX」でございます。
and the thrills of a scream machine: "Wheel Shooter X"!
あー！え、でも絶叫って言ってるけど、すごいノロマですけど...
Ah! But you say "thrill ride", yet it's moving really slowly...
いえいえいえ！これは演出です！
No no no! That's just a performance!
早くやりすぎてしまった！あーー！
We started it too early! Aahh!
そうなんだー。なんか楽しそうに見えない...
I see. It doesn't really look that fun...
え、やば！
Wait, really?!
一応ね、この子にはとんでもない絶叫ギミック隠されてるんで！
Actually, a crazy thrill gimmick is hidden inside this thing!
そうそう！左様でござる！
Yes, exactly! Indeed, gozaru!
ちなみに風真も乗ってみたでござるが、これマジで本気でヤバかったでござる！
By the way, Kazama tried riding it too, and it was seriously, genuinely insane, gozaru!
だからね、ノエル先輩にも是非挑戦して欲しいと思ってるでござる～！
So I really want Noel-senpai to give it a try, gozaru~!
なるほど。ちょっと...見せちゃいますか？
I see. Should we show a bit of it?
見せちゃいますか！やるか！
Shall we show it? Let's do it!
こよりさん、あれやっちゃって！
Koyori-san, do that thing!
オッケーい！
Okaaay!
それではー、ホイールシューター...
Now then, Wheel Shooter...
ださっ！
Lame!
どうですかー！
How's that?!
いつもより多めに回っておりますー！
It's spinning much more than usual~!
死ぬって！
You'll die!
グルグルじゃなくて、あそこでババババーンって感じなの？
It's not just spinning around, it goes "ba-ba-ba-bam" over there?
左様でございます！
Indeed, gozamasu!
いや、なんかちょっと正直不安なんですけど...
Well, honestly, I'm feeling a little anxious...
いやいや、クイズに間違えると、この絶叫ギミック、
No, no! When you get a quiz wrong, this thrill gimmick,
えー、「ホイールシュートださー」が発動するってわけですよ。
the "Wheel Shoot Dasaa" activates, you see!
ださっ！
Dasa?!
ふーん、なるほどね。ちょっとスリルか...でも安全大丈夫なんですか？
Hmm, I see. A bit of thrill... But is it really safe?
いえいえ！安全にはもちろん配慮いたしておりますので、ご安心くださーい！
No, no! We have, of course, taken full safety precautions, so please rest assured!
当たり前でございますよ！
Of course!
ノエル様には早速乗ってもらおうかなと思っております。
We're thinking of having Noel-sama ride it right away.
あの...先生たち？
Um... Senseis?
え、これ6人...
Um, this has six...
6個あるんですけど...
...six seats?
ありますね。1人ずつしか乗れない仕様です。
It does. It's designed for one person at a time.
ちなみに団長1人でもね、2人分の気持ちでいますからね。
By the way, even though Danchou is alone, I carry the feelings of two people.
とある子の魂を背負って、今日は舞っていくんで、勝ちます！
Carrying the soul of a certain someone, I'm soaring today, so I will win!
もちろんもちろん！
Of course, of course!
でも1人なんで、この...どうするんですか？っていう感じ？
But since I'm just one person, what about this... what are we going to do?
さすがに1人では乗せないよね。
We wouldn't make you ride all by yourself, of course.
貸切おめでとうございます！
Congrats on having it reserved for yourself!
恐縮です...って、何人いらっしゃいましたっけ？
I'm flattered... Wait, how many of you are there again?
えー、5人くらいじゃない？
Well, about 5 people, right?
番号！1！
Number off! 1!
はい！2！
Yes! 2!
3！
3!
4！
4!
5！
5!
5人！合わせて6人！
5 people! 6 in total!
みんなで楽しみましょう！イエーーイ！
Let's all enjoy it together! Yay!
せっかくゲストに来ていただいたので、
Since we have a guest here today,
楽しませるっていうことで、みんなも乗りましょう。
to entertain her, let's all ride together!
ありがたいですね！
That's so nice of you!
並んで並んで！
Line up, line up!
先輩からどうぞ！早く乗ってください！
Senpai, after you! Hurry and get on, please!
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
こより様 - はい！
Koyori-sama. - Yes!
holoXは何人でしょうか？
How many members are there in holoX?
えっと、今はなんか6人になってそうだけど、一応5人！
Um, right now it feels like six, but officially five!
一応ね
Officially, yeah.
え、でもね、入るから後で。
Well, she's joining later anyway!
問題。holoXは何年にデビューしました？
Question. What year did holoX debut?
え？何年？
Huh? What year?
何年？いつだっけ？
What year? When was it again?
逆算しろ
Calculate backwards!
あ、2021年！
Ah, 2021!
正解！
Correct!
うん、そうだよねー。
Yeah, that's right.
続いて問題。holoXで初めて3Dお披露目配信をしたのは誰？
Next question. Who in holoX was the first to do a 3D reveal stream?
おー、したの誰？誰？
Ooh, who did it? Who?
この中で、一番… - はい！
Among this group, the first... - Yes!
えー、風真いろは！
Uh, Kazama Iroha!
正解！
Correct!
問題。SS holoXの「SS」とは何の略？
Question. What does the "SS" in SS holoX stand for?
あ、これキツい。シークレット・ソサエティ！
Ah, this is tough... Secret Society!
正解！
Correct!
問題。holoXが侵略予定のエデンの星とは、どの星のこと？
Question. What planet is the "Planet of Eden" that holoX plans to invade?
え？ - え、待って！
Eh? - Wait, what?
我らエデンの星を統べる者なら…
If we are the ones who rule the planet of Eden...
地球！
Earth!
正解！
Correct!
なんだよー！なんだよー！
Come on! What's with this?!
問題。holoXの女幹部といえば、誰のこと？
Question. Who is known as the female executive of holoX?
うーん…えー？誰だっけ？
Umm... huh? Who was that again?
鷹嶺ルイ！
Takane Lui!
正解！
Correct!
え、これ簡単じゃん！
Eh, this is super easy!
問題。風真いろはの刀の名前は？
Question. What is the name of Kazama Iroha's katana?
これは簡単！チャキ丸でござる！
This is easy! Chakimaru de gozaru!
正解！
Correct!
それでは問題。holoXで一番最後にデビューしたのは誰？
Then, next question. Who debuted last in holoX?
お、誰だっけ？誰だっけなー？
Oh, who was it? Who was it again?
忘れてる？
Did you forget?
うーんと…いろは！
Umm... Iroha!
正解！
Correct!
問題。沙花叉クロヱのファンネームは？
Question. What is Sakamata Chloe's fan name?
あ、分かりますよ！飼育員！
Ah, I know this! Keepers!
素晴らしい！正解！
Wonderful! Correct!
問題。holoXはデビュー何周年？
Question. What debut anniversary is holoX celebrating?
2周年でござる！
2nd anniversary de gozaru!
書かれてるぞ、お前！
It's written right there, you fool!
問題。ラプラス・ダークネスの角を除いた身長は？
Question. What is La+ Darknesss's height excluding her horns?
え、どうしよう！嘘でしょ！？えー！ふざけんなよ！
Wait, what do I do?! No way!? Ehh! You've gotta be kidding me!
139だから元が…だから、えっと…
Since she's originally 139... so, um...
うーん、113cmくらい？
Umm, about 113 cm?
残念！不正解！
Too bad! Incorrect!
分かってないよ！
She didn't know!
正解は、139cmです。
The correct answer is 139 cm.
我、139なのお前！
I'm 139, you fool!
それでは、クロヱ様。 - はい…
Now then, Chloe-sama. - Yes...
クロヱ様には、絶叫ギミックを味わっていただきましょう。
Chloe-sama will now experience the scream gimmick.
違う！事故だ！
Wait! It was an accident!
行きますよ。ホイルシュート！
Here we go. Wheel shoot!
キモいでござる
That's creepy de gozaru.
行ってらっしゃい！バイバーイ！
Have a good trip! Bye-bye!
え、帰ってこないのかな？
Is she not coming back?
あれ？何これ？
Huh? What's this?
なんかholoXのことが好きな気分になってきた…
I suddenly feel like I really love holoX...
洗脳されてる！地味！
She's brainwashed! It's so subtle!
この仮面はですね、着けているとholoX愛がどんどん溢れてくる不思議なマスク。
This mysterious mask fills you with more and more holoX love the longer you wear it.
ええー！？
Ehh!?
犯罪ですよ！
That's a crime!
このヘルメットかっこいい！欲しい！
This helmet looks so cool! I want one!
このアトラクションの記念品なのでね。クロヱ様はしばらくこれ着けといてください。
It's a souvenir from this attraction, so Chloe-sama, please keep wearing it for a while.
外したい！
I want to take it off!
顔が隠れちゃいます
Your face is hidden!
皆さん、もっとホイルシューターX楽しみたいですよねー？
Everyone, you want to enjoy Wheel Shooter X more, right?
いやだー！
No way!
それでは皆さん行きますよ。レッツ・ホイルー！
Alright then everyone, here we go. Let's Wheel!
それはダサい…
That's so lame...
それでは問題。
Now, the question.
お、回ってる！ランダムになった！
Oh, it's spinning! It got randomized!
誰からですか？
Who's first?
来たー！
Here it comes!
問題。風真いろはの語尾は？
Question. What is Kazama Iroha's sentence ending?
ござる！
Gozaru!
正解！
Correct!
それでは問題。holoXの頭脳といえば誰のこと？
Then, question. Who is known as the brains of holoX?
はい！はい！博衣こよりだよー！
Yes! Yes! It's Hakui Koyori!
正解！
Correct!
問題。朝こよは基本的に朝何時から配信している？
Question. What time in the morning does AsaKoyo usually stream?
これ間違えたら… - これを間違えていいと思ってる…
If I get this wrong... - She thinks it's okay to get this wrong...
でもヘルメット欲しい
But I still want the helmet.
ヘルメット... ヘルメットなんだい？
Helmet... What helmet?
こよりのヘルメットこっちが被るんだよ！
I'm the one wearing Koyori's helmet!
ヘルメット、11時！ おい！
Helmet, 11:00! Hey!
入った！やった！
It went in! Yay!
それでは...
And now...
正解は7時でした！
The correct answer was 7:00!
あー！そうだよなぁ！
Ah! That's right!
知らなかったなぁ...
I didn't know that...
マジか、知らなかったなぁ...
Seriously? I had no idea...
こよりのことなんてどうでもいいんだよ！
I don't care at all about Koyori!
退場！ やったー！
Ejection! Woohoo!
まさか7時だとは... 知らなかったですねー。
Never thought it'd be 7:00... I didn't know that.
やけくそだ。
She's desperate.
じゃあしょうがない... どういう体勢？！
Well, nothing we can do... What kind of posture is that?!
絶叫ギミックを味わってください！
Please enjoy the screaming gimmick!
はい、いきますよー！
Alright, here we go!
ホイールシュート！
Wheel Shoot!
え、エロ...
Huh, eroti--
いってらっしゃーい！
Have a nice trip!
飛んでった！
She flew off!
しばらく楽しんでおいでー！
Go have fun for a while!
どうよ？ 長いんじゃねえの、これ。
How was it? Isn't this taking pretty long?
戻ってきた！
She's back!
おおおー！
Ooooh!
ラプちゃんかっこいい！ めっちゃ！
Lap-chan looks so cool! Super cool!
なんかでも普段とあんま変わんなくない？
But doesn't she look pretty much the same as usual?
あんま変わんないでござる。
Not much has changed, gozaru.
洗脳足りてなくない？
Isn't the brainwashing not enough?
ホロックス大好き大好き！ めっちゃかっこいい！
I love holoX so much! So cool!
やった、やったー！ 嬉しい！
Yay, yay! I'm so happy!
ただのキッズやめろ！
Stop acting like a little kid!
カッコよくない？
Doesn't it look cool?
かっこいい！ よかったでござるな！
It's cool! Good for you, gozaru!
お前ら羨ましそうに前を見るな！
Stop looking forward so enviously, you guys!
欲しいよ！ 欲しいでしょ！
I want it! You want one too, right?
なんかカッコよく見えてきた！
It's starting to look cool!
じゃあね、ラプ様を置いといて、どんどんやっていきましょう！
Well then, setting Lap-sama aside, let's keep moving forward!
置いてかれた！
I got left behind!
え、またランダム？
Huh, random again?
はい、じゃあ... レッツホイール？
Alright then... Let's Wheel?
え？ なんて？ レッツホイール？ やだなー
Huh? What did you say? Let's Wheel? No thanks...
おい、誰、誰がヘルメット欲しいんだ？ 次！
Hey, who, who wants the helmet next?
はーい！
Me!
欲しい人いっぱいいる！
So many people want it!
はい！ みんなが「はい、はい」言うと...
Yes! When everyone says "Yes, yes"...
外したいやつが当たりたいよ！
The person who wants to get it wrong should get picked!
はい、問題！
Alright, next question!
「音楽が好きで、よく音楽を聴いている」
"Loves music and often listens to music."
これ誰の公式プロフィール？
Whose official profile is this?
誰だろうな？ いろはちゃん？ いろはちゃん？
Who could it be? Iroha-chan? Iroha-chan?
えーでも、風真も音楽好きだし...
But Kazama loves music too...
風真いろは！
Kazama Iroha!
おい馬鹿野郎！
Hey, you idiot!
被りたいだけだろ、お前！
You just want to wear it!
正解は沙花叉クロヱ様でした！
The correct answer was Sakamata Chloe-sama!
そうだったんだ、クロヱごめんね！
Ah, so it was you. Sorry, Chloe!
それではいろは様にも絶叫ギミックを味わっていただきましょう！
Now then, let's have Iroha-sama experience the screaming gimmick as well!
はい、いきますよ！ ホイールシュート！
Alright, here we go! Wheel Shoot!
あら？
Huh?
景色が綺麗だったー！
The view was beautiful!
なんかいい感じだ...
That looks kinda nice...
上がっちゃったな。
It went up.
ただいま、でござる！ うわ、すごい！
I'm back, gozaru! Wow, amazing!
刀似合いそうやん。
That looks like it'd go well with a katana.
これで邪気を退治するでござる！
With this, I shall exorcise evil spirits, gozaru!
みんな喜んでるんだが。
Everyone seems to be enjoying it, though.
ホロックス信者がどんどん増えていってますね！
The number of holoX believers keeps growing!
洗脳されとる... なんでうちのやつ洗脳されるんだろう。
They're brainwashed... Why is our member getting brainwashed?
我々はいいんじゃないか？
Shouldn't we be fine with it?
あれ？ ノエルパイセン？
Huh? Noel-paisen?
ノエルさん、何してるんですか？
Noel-san, what are you doing?
いや、普通にゲームを楽しんで...
Well, I was just enjoying the game...
ノエルさん、ちょっと難しい問題とか...
Noel-san, what about a slightly difficult question...?
そういう流れ？
Is that how this is going?
皆様が問題をいっぱい間違えてもらえれば、ノエル様が...
If everyone gets lots of questions wrong, Noel-sama will...
どんどん問題に答えていってくださいね！
Please keep answering the questions!
似合いそうだしね、騎士だから。フルフェイス似合うよ。
It'll suit her since she's a knight. A full-face visor would look great.
確かに、かっこいい！
Indeed, so cool!
それでは行きましょうか！ レッツホイール？
Shall we get going then? Let's Wheel?
あら、あら...
Oh dear, oh dear...
レッツホイール？ え、なんだろうな？
Let's Wheel? Huh, what could it be?
どんどん難しくなってるの、でも？
Is it getting harder and harder though?
回転に慣れ始めています、我々。
We're starting to get used to the spinning.
ルイだ！ はい、問題です！
It's Lui! Alright, here is your question!
風真いろはのお供のたぬきのお名前は？
What is the name of Kazama Iroha's companion tanuki?
あー、これ何だったっけな...
Ah, what was it again...?
ぽこべぇ！ 正解！
Pokobee! Correct!
はい、問題です！
Alright, next question!
こよりの配信を見ることで摂取できる栄養素はなに？
What nutrient can you absorb by watching Koyori's streams?
こよりうむだ！
Koyorium!
イエーイ！
Yay!
すごいな。
Amazing.
え、次...
Huh, next...
問題。はい。
Question. Here we go.
ラプラス・ダークネス、キリン、カバ
La+ Darknesss, giraffe, hippo.
この中で角がないのは？
Which of these does not have horns?
動物テストやん。
It's an animal quiz!
え、難しくない？holoXの教養テストやって。
Wait, isn't that hard? A general knowledge test on holoX...
ラプラス以外はカバだと思うんですよね。
Aside from La+, I think it's the hippo.
お前ふざけんなよ！
Don't mess with me!
キリンがもうじゃ触んないやつの...
Giraffes have the ones you shouldn't touch...
カバ！
Hippo!
ああー！当たり前だ！
Ahhh! Of course!
問題。
Question.
風真いろはの弓の名前は？
What is the name of Kazama Iroha's bow?
弓って名前あんの？！
The bow has a name?!
保有しているぞ。
She does have one!
これ結構みんな分かんない... 弓？
I bet pretty much nobody knows this... A bow?
でも常識っしょ。
But it's common knowledge!
チャキ丸的な感じだよね、じゃあ。
Then it must be something like Chakimaru.
うつきち！
Utsukichi!
あり得そうな感じにすんな！
Don't make it sound so plausible!
うつきちがいい！
Utsukichi is good!
うつきちでいいじゃん。うつきち可愛い。改名しよう。
Utsukichi sounds great. It's cute. Let's rename it.
どうですか？
How is that?
不正解！
Incorrect!
えー！ということは？
Eh?! Which means?
純粋に分かんない。
I genuinely have no clue.
知らない？
You don't know?
正解は、本人にお聞きください。どうぞ。
For the correct answer, please ask the person herself. Go ahead.
キュウ助！
Kyusuke!
キュウ助！お前ずるい！そんな感じなんだ。
Kyusuke! That's not fair! So that's the kind of name it is.
ほぼ合ってたじゃん！分かんなかった！
It was almost the same! I had no idea!
不正解のノエル様には、絶叫ギミックを味わっていただきましょう！
For the incorrect Noel-sama, let's have her experience the scream ride!
来た来た！行きますよ！
Here it comes! Here we go!
ホイールシュート！
Wheel shoot!
え？！
Huh?!
ああー！
Aaaah!
痛い痛い痛い！
Ow, ow, ow!
いいぞ、いいぞー！
Nice, keep going!
「行ってきます」って言ってたぞ、あの人。楽しんでる？
She said, "I'm off!" right before. Is she having fun?
ちゃんと楽しんでんじゃねえか。アトラクションじゃないから。
She's totally having fun! This isn't an amusement park ride!
ホロックス！
HoloX!
あれ？ホロックス！
Huh? HoloX!
え、洗脳されてない？！
Wait, isn't she brainwashed?!
大好き！
I love you guys!
こえー！救出してくれー！嫌だー！怖い！
Scary! Rescue her! No way! This is terrifying!
嘘やん！甲冑乗っ取られてる！
No way! Her armor is being hijacked!
イエス、マイ・ダーク！
Yes, My Dark!
元々着けてたかのような...
Like she's been wearing it all along...
合ってるよ！
It suits you!
やったー！でも何かちょっと嬉しくなってきた！
Yay! But somehow I'm actually starting to feel happy!
洗脳が効いてるぞ！
The brainwashing is working!
はい、ノエル様が洗脳されたところで、続き行きましょう！
Alright, now that Noel-sama has been brainwashed, let's continue!
次だ！
Next!
あと着けてないのはお二人ですね。
The ones who haven't worn it yet are the remaining two.
ルイ様とこより様かな？
That would be Lui-sama and Koyori-sama?
着けたいんじゃない？なんか仲間外れ... 着けたいんじゃない？
Don't you want to wear it? Being left out and all... Don't you?
はい、じゃあ問題どんどん答えてってください！それでは行きますよ！
Alright, then keep answering the questions! Here we go!
レッツ・ホイール！
Let's wheel!
可愛い感じだ。語尾まで可愛い。ダサかったはずなのに...
That was cute. Even the end was cute. It was supposed to look lame...
止まりやがった！おい、こよりだろ普通！
It stopped! Hey, shouldn't it normally be Koyori?!
問題です。
Here is the question.
holoXで4番目にデビューしたのは誰？
Who was the fourth member to debut in holoX?
全開で行こう！誰だろ？
Let's go all out! Who could it be?
あ、おや？おやおやおや？そうだよ！気付いたわ！
Oh, wait? Oh, oh, oh? That's right! I figured it out!
こよりかなー？誰かなー？
Is it Koyori? Who could it be?
大好きなあの人でしょ？
It's that person you love so much, right?
沙花叉クロヱ！
Sakamata Chloe!
やったー！正解！
Yay! Correct!
よかった！クロヱでよかった！
Thank goodness! I'm glad it was Chloe!
はい、問題。holoX全員での初オリジナル楽曲は？
Alright, question. What is the very first original song by all holoX members?
これ間違えたら...
If you get this wrong...
超エグい問題来た！アーティストだぞ、我ら！
A super brutal question just dropped! We're artists, you know!
うーん... ああ、でもなー...
Hmm... Ah, but still...
迷ってくれてますね。
She seems to be hesitating.
えー、好きな... 好きな楽曲行くかー。
Well, my favorite... Should I just go with my favorite song?
なんで間違い要素増やそうとしてるの？
Why are you trying to increase the chances of getting it wrong?
えー、『迷宮なラビリンス』！
Uh, "Meikyu na Labyrinth"!
2曲目ー！
That's our second song!
さっき歌ってたのにー！
And we just sang it earlier, too!
間違えちゃいました。何でしたっけ？何でしたっけ？
I got it wrong. What was it again? What was it?
『常夜リペイント』でしたー！
It was "Jouya Repaint"!
愛が足りない！足りてなかったかー！
Not enough love! Guess I lacked love!
行きましょー！行きますよ！
Let's do this! Here we go!
反省してもらって。反省します！
Time to reflect on that. I'll reflect on it!
ホイールシュート！
Wheel shoot!
お、ちょっとパターンが...
Oh, the pattern changed a bit...
なんでそんなパターン化してんだよ！
Why are there different patterns?!
ああー！
Aaaah!
ただいまー！楽しんどるやん！
I'm back! She's having fun!
やっと通れたー！
I finally got through!
ああー！可愛い！似合ってる！
Ahhh! Cute! It suits you!
すっぽりハマってる！様になってる！
It fits snugly! It looks great on you!
ちょっと良くない？ねー！
Doesn't it look kind of nice? Yeah!
一番似合ってる！
It suits you the best!
収まりがいい！いいぞ！かっこいい！
It fits so well! Nice! Looking cool!
はい、それでは皆様！
Alright, everyone!
次で間違えたら、最後でございます！
If the next one is wrong, it will be the last!
あー！
Ahhh!
回して！回して！予定調和のようになってる！
Spin it! Spin it! It's like it was all scripted!
バンバン回してください！
Keep spinning it non-stop!
一緒に来て！ラスト、ホイール！
Come along! Last wheel!
かわいい！ずっとやってくれるもんな。ね。
Cute! It always does it for us. Right.
誰だ？誰かな？誰が止まるかな？
Who is it? Who will it be? Who's going to stop?
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
イェーイ！ほらみんな盛り上がって！イェーイ！
Yay! Come on, everyone, get hyped! Yay!
イェーーイ！
Yay!
ロボ子先輩、アキ先輩もようこそホロックスランドへ！イェーイ！
Roboco-senpai, Aki-senpai, welcome to holoX Land! Yay!
イェーーイ！
Yay!
え？だれ、なんか大丈夫かい？
Huh? Is... everything okay?
あれ？心配されてる？
Huh? Are you worried about us?
いやいや、違うんですよー！これはですね、
No, no, that's not it at all! You see...
ホロックスランドの1つのゲームとして開発した、とっても楽しい遊びなのです！
this is a super fun game we developed as one of holoX Land's attractions!
何だよそれ！ / あ、角って吾輩ですよ。
What is that?! / Ah, they're talking about your horns.
ええ？どういうこと？
Eh? What do you mean?
あの、このね、いつも邪魔で、ちょっと視界に入らない角を... / おい！言い過ぎだろ！
Taking these horns that are always in the way and block your view... / Hey! That's going too far!
使って、なんか遊びができないかなーということで、こよりが作りましたー！
we wondered if we could play a game with them, so Koyori made this!
どういうことだよ！
What's that supposed to mean?!
よかったじゃん、視界広くなって。 / 便利に...
Isn't that great? Your field of view opened up. / So convenient...
吾輩別に生えて生まれてきたんだ！
I was born with them growing naturally!
え？でも、なんか聞いたところによると、これって全部ホロックスの新人研修なんでしょ？
Eh? But from what I've heard, isn't all of this just holoX's new recruit training?
ボク別にホロックス入る気ないしなぁ〜
I don't really feel like joining holoX anyway~
ええ〜〜〜！
Ehhh?!
ま、名目は研修、研修という名目の研修なんですけど、
Well, nominally it's training—training under the pretext of training, but...
今回なんと！成功するとご褒美がもらえます！
this time, if you succeed, you get a reward!
おおーー！
Ooooh!
急に盛り上がるじゃん！
You got hyped all of a sudden!
なーにー！
Whaaat?!
こいつら元気だなー。
Look at their energy.
勝つぞー！
We're gonna win!
え、でもさー、これってさー何したらいいの？なんか...
Eh, but what are we supposed to do in this? Like...
これね、なんか、ま、見たことあるような記憶があったりなかったりみたいな感じなんだけど、ちょっと教えてほしいな。
This thing... I feel like I might or might not have seen it before somewhere, but could you explain it?
気になりますよねー。それじゃあ、ご説明させていただきましょうー！
You're curious, right? Well then, allow us to explain!
おー！ / よろしくー！
Ooh! / Please do!
えー、この爆発！ムカムカ頭脳、
Um, this "Explosion! Mukamuka Brain",
こちらは、えー、2人1組で挑戦をしてもらうゲームとなっております。
is a game where you challenge it in pairs of two.
おーー！
Ooh!
ラプラスの本来ね、このためにある角を、
Taking La+'s horns, which were originally made for this purpose,
後ろにあるこのコースにですね、
through this course behind us...
コースのフレームにぶつからないように、こう、移動をさせて、
you must guide them so they don't hit the course frame,
無事ゴールができればクリアとなります！
and if you successfully reach the goal, you clear it!
面白そう！
Sounds fun!
もし角がフレームにぶつかってしまった場合、なんと大爆発してしまいますので！
If the horns happen to touch the frame, it will trigger a massive explosion!
えええーーー！
Eeeeh?!
大爆発？ / 楽しみー！
A massive explosion? / Sounds fun!
急にテンション上がった！
Suddenly everyone's so hyped!
これクリアしたご褒美って言ってたけど、何がもらえるの？
You mentioned a reward for clearing this, what do we get?
なんとですねー！このホロックスランド開園記念で、
Well! To commemorate the grand opening of holoX Land...
10億ヤマダラーをプレゼントいたします！
we will present you with 1 Billion Yamada-llars!
待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
ヤマダラー？え、ヤマダラーって何これ？
Yamada-llars? Wait, what are Yamada-llars?
え、これメモ帳じゃなくて？
Wait, isn't this just a notepad?
メモ帳やね。キッズの遊ぶものだよね？
It is a notepad. A toy for kids, right?
ちょっと待って、これ吾輩の顔印刷してあるんだけど。
Wait a minute, my face is printed on this!
え、これ本当に要る？ / ホロックスランドで使えます！
Wait, do we really need this? / You can spend it at holoX Land!
ちょっと待って！勝手に作られて勝手に悪口言われてるんですけど！
Wait a second! You made this without asking and now you're insulting it!
いいじゃん、ビジュいいよ！かわいい！
It's fine! The visual looks great! Cute!
どうですか？やりたくなりました？
How about it? Do you feel like doing it now?
いや、でもちょっとラプを爆発させたいって気持ちが...
Well, but I kind of feel like making Lap-chan explode...
なんでだよ！吾輩は実験台か！
Why?! Am I a guinea pig?!
それでは早速、えー、ロボ子とアキパイセンに準備をしていただきましょう。ご準備お願いします！
Well then, without further ado, let's have Roboco and Aki-paisen get ready. Please take your positions!
お任せくださーい！
Leave it to us!
イェーイ！勝つぞー！ / 発破！発破！
Yay! We're gonna win! / Blast off! Blast off!
発破！発破！
Blast off! Blast off!
爆発！ムカムカ角 完全攻略できたら10億YMD
[Explosion! Mukamuka Horns - 1 Billion YMD for Clear]
ちょっと待って、どういう状況これ？！おい！
Wait a minute, what kind of situation is this?! Hey!
さあ、お2方、ご準備はできたでしょうかー？
Now then, you two, are you ready?
う、重っ！腕が折れちゃう！
S-So heavy! My arms are gonna snap!
なんで持ち上げたんだよ！
Why did you lift me up?!
お、重い！ / おー、すげえ！持ち上げた！
S-So heavy! / Oh, awesome! They lifted her!
実際に持ってみてどうですかー？
How does it feel actually holding her?
棒立ちなんて言えない、重いな！
I can't say she's light as a board—she's heavy!
あー、ロボ子さん助けて！
Ah, Roboco-san, help!
持ち直して... 持ち直してもダメか... 重かったわ...
Let's readjust... Even readjusting doesn't work... She was really heavy...
持ちやすいですかー？
Is she easy to hold?
持ちづらいよ、ラプちゃん！ / 持ちづらいね。
You're hard to hold, Lap-chan! / Yeah, hard to hold.
吾輩別に棒じゃないからね！
I'm not a stick, you know!
すごい、え、硬い！今日どうしたの、ラプちゃん？
Amazing... wait, you're stiff! What happened to you today, Lap-chan?
気づいたらなんか黒づくめの集団が吾輩を担ぎ始めて...
Before I knew it, a group dressed in black started carrying me, and...
ピーンとなったんだ。 / 棒の役勢ですからね。
So you stiffened right up. / She is playing the role of the rod, after all.
ということで、特に制限時間はございませんので、
So with that said, there is no particular time limit,
慎重に頑張っていただければなと思います！
so please proceed carefully!
ラプ、お前動くなよ！ / 頑張れー！
Lap, don't you move! / Good luck!
動けないんだって！動けたら逃げてるよ！
I can't move anyway! If I could move, I'd have run away!
それでは、爆発！ムカムカ頭脳、スタート！
And now, Explosion! Mukamuka Brain, START!
オーケー！まっすぐ行ってー
Okay! Go straight—
ぐるーっと行きますよー
We're looping around~
まだ許してないからな、吾輩！
I still haven't forgiven you guys!
いい感じ、いい感じ！戻して、戻して！
Looking good, looking good! Bring it back, bring it back!
慎重にゆっくりね！
Be careful and take it slow!
ゆっくり、ゆっくり、ゆっくり... / 結構うまいじゃん！
Slowly, slowly, slowly... / They're pretty good!
ふざけんなよマジで！
Seriously, stop messing around!
下がって、下がって！そうそうそう、余裕余裕！
Back up, back up! Yeah, yeah, yeah, easy peasy!
ちょ、これ顔に当たる！顔に当たるってこれ！
Wait, this is hitting my face! It's gonna hit my face!
大丈夫、大丈夫！ / 顔バイスってなんだよ！
It's fine, it's fine! / What do you mean by "face vice"?!
どういうこと？当たり判定角しかないの？
What do you mean? Is the hitbox only on the horns?
角当てちゃったってことですね！ / シンプルに痛いだろ！
So you hit the horns! / That just plain hurts!
次行く？次。せーの！
Moving to the next? Next. Ready, go!
わあああーーー！！ / ふざけんな！！ / ラプ様ーー！！
Waaaaah!! / Stop messing around!! / Lap-samaaa!!
待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
おい、挟んだ。大丈夫？いいのそれ？
Hey, it got caught. Are you okay? Is that allowed?
刺さってる、刺さってる！
It's piercing it! It's piercing it!
刺さってるー！
It's totally stuck in there!
うわあああああ！
Waaaaah!
ちょっと待って...
Hold on a second...
焦げた匂いすんだけどラプラス。
La+ is smelling something burning.
いやお前らもだよ！お前らも爆発してんだよ！
Hey, you guys too! You blew up too!
こっちのほうが強い
Our blast is stronger.
やめて、やめて！
Stop, stop!
なんでこの状況で笑っていられるんだよ！
How can you be smiling in this situation?!
うわあああああ！
Waaaaah!
ふざけんな！
You gotta be kidding me!
生きてるか？生きてるか？
Are you alive? Are you alive?
なんでやり切ったみたいな顔...
Why do you have that "mission accomplished" look...?
やり切ったー！
We accomplished it!
超やり切ったよ。
We totally saw it through.
さすがです先輩方！
As expected of our seniors!
やり切った、やり切った！
We did it, we did it!
二人共ちょっと...やり切ったじゃない！
Both of you, hold on... You didn't accomplish anything!
じ、自分の顔見てみろよ！
T-Take a look at your own faces!
え？これでめっちゃ真っ黒なんだけどー！
Eh? But they're completely pitch black!
なんか焦げ臭いか、ちょっと。
It does smell kind of burnt, I guess.
焦げ臭いどころじゃねえよ！
It's way worse than just smelling burnt!
普通に事故ってたぞおい！
That was a total disaster, hey!
あまりにも強すぎる。
It was far too intense.
さすがにこれは失敗かなー。
I guess this was a failure after all.
そりゃそうだろ！ラプラス、じっとしとけよお前！
Of course it was! La+, hold still next time!
動く、動くのかー。
So it actually moves, huh...
やってみてどうでしたか？
How did it feel trying it out?
いや、思っていたより難しいかもしんない。
Honestly, it might be harder than I thought.
そうね、角がね、
Yeah, the horns...
でかい、邪魔。
...are huge and get in the way.
邪魔って言うな！
Don't call them "in the way"!
お気づきになられましたか？
Did you finally notice?
やっと気付いたわ！
We finally noticed!
てめーらオモチャにしやがって、許さねーからな！
You jerks treated me like a toy, I won't forgive you!
なんか言ってるよー。
She's saying something~
やめろ！揺らすな！
Stop! Don't shake me!
揺らすな！やめろー！
Don't shake me! Stop it!
じゃ次、ちょっと交代してみましょうか。
Well then, let's swap out next.
まだやんの？これ...
We're still doing this...?
はい、じゃあクロヱと、いろは、行きましょう。
Alright, Chloe and Iroha, let's go.
一番不安、一番不安！
I'm the most nervous, the most nervous!
お手本を見せてあげてくださいよ、先輩方に。
Show our seniors a good example!
おい揺れる、揺れる！ちょ、やめ...やめてよー！
Hey, it's swaying, it's swaying! St-stop it!
よいしょ、いろはちゃん持って。
Heave-ho, grab hold, Iroha-chan.
私を弄びに来てるんですか？
Did you just come here to play around with me?
はい、よいしょ！
Alright, heave-ho!
よーい、よい、よい！
Yo-i, yo-i, yo-i!
爆発！ムカムカ角 完全攻略できたら10億YMD
[Explosion! Irritating Horns - 1 Billion YMD if cleared!]
クロヱ、いろは、準備は大丈夫ですかー？自信はどうでしょう？
Chloe, Iroha, are you ready? How's your confidence?
爆発したら巻き込まれるって聞いたんでマジで嫌なんですけど、ちょっと爆発させてみたいです。
I heard I'd get caught in the blast so I really hate it, but... I kind of want to see it blow up.
人殺しー！
Murderer!
好奇心が勝っているようで。
Sounds like curiosity won out.
ま、なんとかなるっしょ！
Well, it'll work out somehow!
じゃあね、ちょっと見本を見せてもらいましょーう！
Now then, let's see an example from you two!
それでは、爆発ムカムカ角、スタート！
And so, Explosion! Irritating Horns, start!
頼むぞ、頼むぞ...
I'm counting on you, counting on you...
待っていろはちゃん、命かかってる、命かかってる！
Wait, Iroha-chan, lives are on the line, lives are on the line!
魚の命が... ラプラスはどうでもいいんだ。
The orca's life is... Guess La+ doesn't matter.
ごめん、確かに。お前ら本当に...！
Sorry, you're right. You guys, seriously...!
慎重にいこう、慎重に。
Let's go carefully, carefully.
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ...
Wait, wait, wait...
大丈夫これ？
Is this okay?
え、これどう？これどう？
Eh, how about this? How about this?
いける、いける！
We can make it, we can make it!
怖い！一番怖い！
Scary! This is terrifying!
顔に近いよ！
It's so close to my face!
危ねえ！待っていろはちゃん、まだまだ...
Dangerous! Wait, Iroha-chan, not yet, not yet...
お前ら一回深呼吸しろ！
Take a deep breath, you two!
深呼吸しろ！ウチらの将来のプラン...
Take a deep breath! Our future plans are...
待って、どこで行く？
Wait, where should we go through?
これの次で行こう！オッケー！せーの！
Let's go after this one! Okay! One, two...!
行くよ！うわあああああ！
Here goes! Waaaaah!
わざとじゃない、わざとじゃない！
It wasn't on purpose! It wasn't on purpose!
わざとだー！わざとじゃないよー！
It WAS on purpose! No it wasn't!
わざとだー！
It totally was!
はい！おーい！残念ながら...いや、「やり切った」じゃないんだよ！
Alright! Hey! Unfortunately... No, don't give me "mission accomplished"!
あー、こうやって真っ黒になったんだ。
Ah, so that's how you get covered in soot.
はい、残念ながら失敗となりまーす！
Yes, unfortunately, this is a failure!
残念とかじゃねえから！
"Unfortunately" my foot!
お前の角がでっけえからでござる！
It's because your horns are huge de gozaru!
お前...！
You...!
もっと慎重にやれよ下手くそ。
Be more careful, you clumsy fools.
でもラプラスらしいよ？
Well, that's very La+-like though.
角でけえ！角でかすぎるんだよ！
The horns are huge! Way too huge!
角でけえはさっきも聞いたって！削ってくれ、頼む！
I already heard the "horns are huge" earlier! Just file them down, please!
次、ちょっとラプラスからね、愛されているこよりと、そしてまあ信頼を置かれているルイでやりましょうか。
Next, let's have Koyori, who is beloved by La+, and Lui, who is trusted by her, give it a shot.
いや、ここは頭脳をね、見せて行きましょうよ！エリートにやっていこう！
Yeah, let's show off our brains here! Let's do this like elites!
じゃあお姉さん組、ちょっとこのちびを...
Alright, big sister duo, take this little one...
頼むよ、頭脳派組...
I'm counting on you, brainiac team...
ぎくしゃくしてる！
You're so awkward!
扱いきれてないです！
They can't handle me properly!
泣きながらオギャーって言っていいんだよ？
You can cry and wail like a baby, you know?
いや、ちょっとこの状況はさすがに喜べない...
No, in this situation I really can't be happy...
爆発！ムカムカ角 完全攻略できたら10億YMD
[Explosion! Irritating Horns - 1 Billion YMD if cleared!]
え、ちょっと本当に信じてるからね？
Hey, I'm really trusting you guys, okay?
何を？
With what?
いや、お前らを！お前らをだよ！
With you guys! I'm trusting YOU!
何を信じられてるのかな？
I wonder what you're trusting us with?
お前らはクリアすることだよ！
To clear this course!
じゃあ、頑張りましょう！
Well then, let's do our best!
54歳の絆、頑張りましょう！
With the bond of 54-year-olds, let's do our best!
頑張れー！
Hang in there!
一番不安
I'm the most anxious.
じゃあ、準備できましたー？
Well then, are you ready?
オッケー！
Okay!
はーい！それでは、爆発ムカムカ棒、スタート！
Alright! Then, the exploding Mukamuka Rod, start!
ゆっくりね、ゆっくり
Slowly, slowly now.
早くこの地獄から解放してくれ！
Hurry up and release me from this hell!
危ない危ない…うまいかも！
Watch out, watch out... This might actually go well!
いいよいいよ、うまいかも！
Looking good, we're actually doing great!
そうそうそう！これキレて怒ってるとこ
That's it! This is the part where it gets angry.
さすがにここは早いよ
As expected, it's fast here.
お、お、お、おお！うまい、うまい！
Oh, oh, oh, whoa! Nice, nice!
丁寧！ラプラスを信頼して
So careful! Put your trust in Laplus.
ちょっと安心感を感じる、母性がね
I actually feel kind of safe, maternal love, huh.
危ない危ない！ちょっと怖い怖い怖い…
Watch out! It's kinda scary, scary, scary...
せーの！
Ready, set...
あああああーーー！
Aaaaaaahhhh!
痛い痛い痛い！
It hurts, hurts, hurts!
すげえ！行けそう！
Amazing! We can make it!
いや、もうクリアでいいよ！
No, just count it as a clear already!
いいよ！ぎゃあああーー！
Looking good— AAAAAHHHH!
ラプラスー！
Laplus~~!
何回やればいいんだよ！
How many times do I have to do this?!
いや、めちゃくちゃ良かったんじゃない？
No, wasn't that actually really good?
どうでしたか？どういう番組？
How was it? What kind of show is this anyway?
どう、どうだった？
How was it?
案外簡単だったね
It was surprisingly easy, wasn't it?
余裕だった！恥ずかしくないんか！
It was a breeze! Aren't you embarrassed at all?!
全員こうなるんだね
Everyone ends up looking like this, huh.
ふざけんなよ！エキサイダー
Stop messing around! Exciting!
途中までね、焦げなかったし、すごかったよ
Until midway through, you didn't get burned, it was amazing!
そう、しかもみんな失敗してたところを、我々は成功しましたから！
Yeah, plus we actually succeeded where everyone else failed!
ええー！優勝！イエーイ！
Eeh?! We won! Yay!
これが絆ってことよ！ねえ、ラプちゃん
This is what bonds are all about! Right, Lap-chan?
レベル低すぎだろ
The bar is way too low!
はい、ってことで、あ、ラプラスさん体戻ったね！
Alright, so, ah, Laplus-san, your body is back to normal!
本当だよ、ふざけんなよ！
Seriously! Stop messing around!
また黒ずくめの人たちに戻されたけどね
Though she was restored by the people in black again.
さっきのも良かったけどね、あの形可愛かった
The previous one was nice too though, that shape was cute.
ずっと持っときたかったわ
I wanted to keep holding it forever.
まあやってみたわけですけど、どうでしたか？ロボ子先輩、アキ先輩！
Well, we gave it a try, but how was it, Roboco-senpai, Aki-senpai?
でも、ラプラス持ってるのちょっと楽しかったよねー
But holding Laplus was kinda fun, wasn't it~
思った以上に楽しくて、今もう一回やりたいもん
It was more fun than expected, I want to do it once more right now!
ええー！本当に？！もう一回カチカチになってよ
Eeh?! Seriously?! Turn rock-hard one more time!
次は爆発しないよ！
Next time it won't explode!
もう誰も信じられない！誰も信じない！
I can't trust anyone anymore! I don't trust anyone!
アキロゼ先輩は信用ならんぞ、あれは
Aki Rosenthal-senpai cannot be trusted at all, seriously.
なんか好き勝手やれるって楽しいなって思いました
I thought doing whatever we wanted was really fun.
分かる分かる、日頃の恨みというか
I get it, I get it. Or rather, daily grudges...
やったー！うるせえ！バカどもが！
Yay! Shut up, you idiots!
というわけですね、あの、ホロメンの皆さん！
So with that said, um, everyone in hololive!
こちらのムカムカ頭脳がクリアできれば、holoX大総帥の席をご用意しております！
If you can clear this Mukamuka Brain, we have the seat of holoX Supreme Commander ready for you!
ないないない！奪われる！
No no no! It'll be taken away!
ないよー！
There's no way!
はい、自信のある人はね、練習して是非…
Yes, if you're confident, please practice and...
お越しください！holoXランドにお越しください！
Please come! Please come to holoX Land!
というわけで、次なる挑戦者は…誰だ！
And so, the next challenger is... who?!
来るな！誰だ！
Don't come! Who is it?!
やめちまえ！やめちまえ！
Just quit it! Quit it!
誠に遺憾です。
It is truly regrettable.
本当に遺憾です。
Truly regrettable.
でも楽しかったね。お前らだけだよ楽しかったのは！
But it was fun. You guys are the only ones who had fun!
たまには役に立つ角でござるな。たまにはって何だよ！うるせえ！
Those horns are useful once in a while de gozaru. What do you mean "once in a while"?! Shut up!
ま、でもね、一応この後は、貴様らお待ちかねの…ライブ！
Well, but anyway, after this is what you've all been waiting for... a live show!
ライブ！ライブ！チャンネルはそのまま！
Live! Live! Stay tuned to this channel!
があるんですが…その前に、ここで我輩たちに関するお知らせが、もういっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱいあるんだ！
We have that, but before then, right here we have lots and lots and lots and lots of announcements regarding us!
心して聞くように！
Listen closely!
じゃあ、ルイ、お願いします。あ、私？丸投げだね。
Then, Rui, if you please. Ah, me? Dumping it all on me, huh.
はい！じゃあ、まずはholoXの活動2周年記念グッズの紹介をいたします！
Yes! Well, first off, we'll introduce holoX's 2nd Anniversary Commemorative Goods!
イエーイ！ということで、こちら！
Yay! So, here it is!
はい！ということで、このイラストめちゃくちゃかっこよくないですかー？
Yes! So, isn't this illustration super cool?
先日ね、紹介したヘッドセットをつけた描き下ろしイラストになっております！
It's a newly drawn illustration featuring the headsets we introduced the other day!
黒井ススム先生に描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
It was drawn for us by Kuroi Susumu-sensei! Thank you very much!
お尻触られた！
Someone touched my butt!
では、グッズも早速見ていきましょうか！
Then, shall we take a look at the goods right away?
まずはこちら、チェンジングキーホルダー！角度を変えるとヘッドセットからマスクに変身するという、かっこいいキーホルダーになっております！
First is this: Changing Keychain! As you change the angle, it transforms from headset to mask, making it a super cool keychain!
すごい！そうそうそう、角度でね。反射のやつだ
Awesome! Yeah yeah, by angle. It's the reflective kind.
修学旅行で買うやつみたいな。めっちゃ可愛い！
Like the ones you buy on school trips! Super cute!
欲しい！欲しいでしょ？欲しい！
I want one! You want it, right? I want one!
いろはの分もあります。4人分あります。
Iroha's is here too. We have all four of them.
写ってよかったね！
Good thing you made it in!
ありがとう！よかったー！
Thank you! I'm so glad!
こちらはそれぞれ単体で販売されますので、
These are sold individually,
推しのキーホルダーを手にとっていただければと思います。
so please pick up your favorite member's keychain.
もちろん5人全員集めていただくのも大歓迎です！
Of course, collecting all five is more than welcome!
欲しい！欲しい！
I want them! I want them!
そしてそして、こちらをご覧ください。どうぞ！
And next, please take a look at this. Here you go!
はい、5人揃ったイラストのラバーマットが登場です！
Yes, here is a rubber mat featuring all five of us!
おー！いいマット！でかいよ！
Oh! What a great mat! It's huge!
えー仕事や勉強、ゲームをする際のデスクマットにもお使いいただけます…
You can use it as a desk mat for work, studying, or gaming...
何やってんだよ！
What are you guys doing?!
どうですか、このほら…
How do you like it? Look at this...
めっちゃかっこいい！
It's so cool!
かっこいいでしょ！欲しかったよね、きっと。
Cool, right? You definitely wanted one, didn't you?
はい、そしてお次は実に我々っぽいグッズですよ。こちら！
All right, next up is a piece of merch that really fits us. Look here!
なんと、holoXのアタッシュケースが登場です！
Amazingly, a holoX attaché case has arrived!
すげー！秘密結社っぽいでしょ！
Awesome! It feels so secret society-like!
外側にはholoXのロゴ、
On the outside is the holoX logo,
中にはアジトの鍵が入っております！
and inside is the key to our hideout!
え！？鍵！？セキュリティ！セキュリティ！
Huh?! A key?! Security! Security!
じゃあでも、来れるもんなら来てみろってこと？
Wait, does that mean "come on in if you dare"?
特定されたらね、入られちゃうってことでw
If they find the location, they can get right in, haha!
中のクッションはですね、取り外しができますので、
The cushion inside is removable,
イベントなんかでも使えるんじゃないかなと思います。
so I think you can even use it for events.
えー！楽しみー！
Wow! Looking forward to it!
はい、そして最後はこちらです。
Yes, and here is our last item.
デビュー記念でも販売しましたピンバッジ、皆さん覚えておりますでしょうか？
Do you all remember the pin badge we sold for our debut?
あー！あったね！
Ah! That's right!
2周年記念バージョンが登場しております。
The 2nd Anniversary version is here!
なのでね、デビュー記念のものと合わせてコンプリートしていただくのと、
So you can complete your set together with the debut one,
あと途中からholoXファンになった方に関しては…
and for those who became holoX fans along the way...
大丈夫ですか？見切れてる人もいますけどw
Are you guys okay? Someone's getting cut out of frame, haha!
小さくなってるよ！はい！
I got smaller! Yes!
ぜひぜひこの機会に買っていただければなと思います。
We'd love it if you take this chance to get one.
かっこいい！
So cool!
ただいま紹介した2周年記念グッズはこの後22時より販売開始になります。
The 2nd anniversary merch we just showed will go on sale at 10:00 PM today.
気になった方はぜひチェックしてみてくださいね。
If you're interested, please be sure to check them out!
お願いしまーす！
Please check it out!
戻ろ、戻ろ。
Let's get back in position.
博衣こよりさん、よろしくお願いします！
Hakui Koyori-san, take it away!
はーい！
Okaaay!
今回なんと！こよの、大好きな、あのイベントが開催されることになりましたー！
This time, believe it or not, Koyo's absolute favorite kind of event has been decided!
おー！何ですか！？
Ooh! What is it?!
まずは、こちらの映像をご覧ください！ドンドン！
First, please take a look at this video! Ta-da!
これはキミたちへの挑戦状だ
This is a challenge to all of you.
ぼくたち秘密結社holoXが作った、極上のラビリンス！
A supreme labyrinth created by us, Secret Society holoX!
たくさんの謎が仕掛けられたラビリンスの奥に――
Deep within the labyrinth riddled with countless riddles...
キミはたどり着けるかな？
Will you be able to make it to the end?
必要なのは知恵とヒラメキと、風真たちへの忠誠心！
What you need is wisdom, inspiration, and loyalty to Kazama and the others!
貴様らの挑戦を待っているぞ！！
We await your challenge!!
イエス、マイダーク！でござる！
Yes, My Dark! De gozaru!
強制力あったからね / ちょっと抗えない…
It was quite compelling. / You really couldn't resist it...
はい！ということで、holoXの謎解きイベントが開催決定しましたー！
Yes! With that, a holoX riddle-solving event has been officially confirmed!
イエーイ！すげー！
Yay! / Awesome!
その名も、『秘密結社holoXからの招待状 迷宮なラビリンスからの脱出 in 渋谷』！
Its name is: "Invitation from Secret Society holoX: Escape from the Labyrinthine Labyrinth in Shibuya"!
おー！
Ooh!
holoXのオリジナル楽曲『迷宮なラビリンス』の世界観の中で行われる、謎解き脱出ゲームになっております！
It's a riddle-solving escape room game set in the world of holoX's original song "Labyrinthine Labyrinth"!
こちらの謎解きイベントは、1週間後の12月9日から、渋谷BEAMの4階で開催いたします！
This riddle-solving event will take place starting in one week on December 9th, at Shibuya BEAM 4F!
なんとイベント参加チケットは本日22時から販売開始なので、よーいどんで！
And event participation tickets go on sale tonight at 10:00 PM, on your mark, get set, go!
やばいやばい！行かなきゃ！ / 詳しくは特設サイトをチェックしてみてください！
Oh no, we gotta go! / Please check the special website for details!
さらに、イベントグッズも発売します！
Furthermore, event merchandise will also go on sale!
うわー！めっちゃある！すごい！
Whoa! / There are so many! / Amazing!
グッズ化嬉しいね / めっちゃいい！
So glad it got turned into merch! / That's so great!
『迷宮なラビリンス』グッズ、今までなかったから
Since we didn't have any "Labyrinthine Labyrinth" merch until now.
ね、この2曲目の楽曲のグッズとしてもぜひチェックしてください！
Yes, please check out the merch for our second original song as well!
イベントやグッズ情報について詳しくは特設サイト、ホロライブ公式Xの告知をご覧ください！
For details on the event and merchandise, please see the special website and Hololive official X announcements!
ぜひ皆さん参加してくださいねー！
Everyone, please be sure to participate!
続いてはクロたんお知らせ、お願いします！まだまだあるよ！
Next, Chloe-tan, the announcement please! There's still more!
はい！なんかめちゃくちゃスペシャルな内容になってるそうなので、皆さん驚いてください！驚けー！
Yes! Apparently this is super special content, so everyone get ready to be amazed! Be amazed!
驚くぞー！
We're ready!
うわー！！
Whoaaa!!
12月31日大晦日に、なんと地上波とホロライブ公式チャンネルで、我々holoXがメインのスペシャルショートアニメが放送されます！
On New Year's Eve, December 31st, a special short anime featuring us, holoX, will air on terrestrial TV and the official Hololive channel!
すごーい！地上波！？たつき監督だ！
Amazing! / On terrestrial TV?! / Directed by Tatsuki!
わー！ / うわー！
Whoa! / Yay!
めちゃめちゃ熱い展開！
This is an insanely exciting development!
たつき監督やばい！やばい！
Director Tatsuki is insane! That's crazy!
公式Xからの情報を待っててください！乞うご期待！
Please stay tuned for more info on the official X account! Look forward to it!
ということで次のお知らせはいろはちゃん！
And with that, the next announcement is from Iroha-chan!
はーい！ではですね、風真からお知らせさせていただきまーす！
Okay! Now then, Kazama will make the announcement!
はい！なんとholoXとホロプラスの連動プレゼントキャンペーンがスタートするでござるー！
Yes! A joint holoX and holoplus giveaway campaign is starting, gozaru!
皆様、ホロプラスは使ってくれてますかー？
Is everyone using holoplus?
使ってるー！ / イェーイ！
We're using it! / Yay!
抽選で13名に「hololive friends with u」やアクリルスタンドなど、holoXグッズが当たりまーす！
13 lucky winners will receive holoX merch, including "hololive friends with u" plushies and acrylic stands!
応募期間は12月2日から来年の1月9日まで！
The entry period runs from December 2nd to January 9th next year!
詳しい応募方法はホロプラスでご確認ください！
Please check holoplus for detailed application instructions!
ホロプラスには「マイ推し」機能っていうのがあるので、ぜひholoXをマイ推しに追加してほしいでござるー！
holoplus has a "My Oshi" feature, so please be sure to add holoX to your My Oshi, gozaru!
え、5個もらえるんだ。すごいね。
Wow, you get all 5? That's awesome.
当たるでござるよ！飾ってくだされー！
You can win them, gozaru! Please put them on display!
言えたね！ホロプラス言えたね！
You said it! You were able to say "holoplus"!
ホロプラス言えて偉い！ちゃんとお知らせ言えたね！
Good job saying "holoplus"! You delivered the announcement well!
マジでちょっと情報が多すぎ！多すぎるね！
Seriously, that was way too much info! Way too much!
多かったんですけども、全部すごい情報なんで！
There was a lot, but it's all incredible news!
そう、みんなチェックしてくださーい！
That's right, everyone make sure to check it out!
チェックお願いしまーす！
Please check it out!
これからもholoX一同、全力で頑張っていくので、どうぞよろしくお願いします！
All of us in holoX will continue giving it our all, so please keep supporting us!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Thank you so much!
よし！お知らせもしたし、
All right! Now that the announcements are done...
最後はライブで締め括るぞー！
We'll finish things off with a live performance!
行くぞー！ / イェーイ！
Let's go! / Yay!
そっちキッチン！そっちキッチン！走れー！
That's the kitchen! That way is the kitchen! Run!
La La PaTa Pa La La PaTa
La La PaTa Pa La La PaTa Pa
La La PaTa Pa-La-Pu-Ta Pa-Ra-Pa Ta-Pa
La La PaTa Pa-Ra-Pu-Ta Pa-Ra-Pa Ta-Pa
迷宮なラビリンス
Labyrinthine labyrinth
残された招待状
The left-behind invitation,
秘密で秘匿の異次元マンションへ
to the secret and confidential other-dimensional mansion.
ガタガタ騒ぐな ご案内
Don't make a racket; let me guide you,
No Pain, No Gain
暗示
Suggestion
狙うは真骨頂 ホークアイ
Aiming for the true essence with a hawk eye.
迫る罠はウォークライ
The closing trap is a war cry.
報酬上に突破
Breaking through towards the reward,
翻弄 どうだろうの走馬灯
toyed with, how about a revolving lantern?
藻屑に取り込まれていくよ
Getting swallowed up into the debris,
刻印でござる！
It's a seal, gozaru!
順調な見学ツアー
A tour going smoothly,
ドアからドアへ誘導中
being guided from door to door.
探すごちゃより 今日は
Rather than a chaotic search, today...
響け 笑い声
Let our laughter resound!
La La PaTa Pa La La PaTa
La La PaTa Pa La La PaTa Hey!
La La PaTa Pa-La-Pu-Ta Pa-Ra-Pa Ta-Pa
La La PaTa Pa-Ra-Pu-Ta Pa-Ra-Pa Ta-Pa
つまり保険
In short, insurance!
力こそパワー！
Power is might!
素敵な迷宮のラビリンス
A wonderful labyrinth of labyrinths,
です
it is!
並び立つシルエット
Silhouettes standing side by side.
恐怖で切断だ Wi-Fi
Severed by fear: Wi-Fi.
これマジで最強ルームだけど
Even though this really is the ultimate room,
風真の回路も普通に
Kazama's circuit is also just normally...
危ないって
It's dangerous!
ワンショット
One shot,
ワンキル
one kill!
虚実を踊るマリオネット
Marionettes dancing between truth and lies.
落ちる部屋はナントカ
The room we fall into is whatever...
論外は眼中にないが落雷
The irrelevant isn't in our sight, but lightning strikes!
アカンくない？ 藻屑に取り込まれてく
Isn't this bad? Getting swallowed into the debris!
迷える子羊たちにお砂糖、スパイス、それにピンクなものいっぱいでハイになれるドリンクできたよー！
For all you lost lambs, I made a drink with sugar, spice, and plenty of pink things to get you high!
ロックで飲んでくださいね、holoXだけに。
Please drink it on the rocks—because holoX!
ささ皆殿、飲むでござる！
Come on everyone, drink up, gozaru!
いや、お前が飲むんかい！
Wait, you're the one drinking it?!
じゃ、とりあえず、乾杯ー！
Well, for now... cheers!
乾杯ー！
Cheers!
鏡の回路から
From the circuit of mirrors,
展望の迷所へと
to the scenic labyrinth,
振り返られる勝者 見果てろ
the victor who can look back, see it through!
響け 笑い声
Let our laughter resound!
お前たちもな！
You guys too!
La La PaTa Pa La La PaTa
La La PaTa Pa La La PaTa Hey!
La La PaTa Pa-La-Pu-Ta Pa-Ra-Pa Ta-Pa
La La PaTa Pa-Ra-Pu-Ta Pa-Ra-Pa Ta-Pa
雑踏へ
Into the bustling crowd,
5人の元 肩組んで
with the five of us, linking arms,
声を高らかに La PaTa
raise our voices loud and high: La PaTa!
エデンの海を越えるため
To cross the Eden Sea,
つまり本件
in other words, in this case,
屈託抱いた
harboring worries,
敵な眩暈の
it's a hostile dizziness,
スーパーフューチャーパーティラビリンス！
Super Future Party Labyrinth!
Yes! holoX!
ん？何だこれ？何だこれー！
Huh? What's this? What is this?!
こよりが作りましたー！
Koyori made it~!
お前かよ！
It was you?!
えー！かっこいいでしょー！
Ehh! Looks cool, right?!
じゃあありがとう、またねー
Well then, thanks, see ya~
え、なんでなんでなんで！？爆発するもん、これ！
Eh, why, why, why?! Because this is gonna explode!
爆発…押してよ！押してよ！
Explode...? Press it! Press it!
でもさ、なんでいろはがそっち側に付いてんだよ！
Wait, why is Iroha taking her side?!
なんでいろはが押せ押せなんだよ！
Why is Iroha egging us on to press it?!
いや絶対危ないって！押してみなよ！
No, this is definitely dangerous! Try pressing it!
こういうのはさぁ…人殺しだからな！
Things like this... You're like a murderer!
総帥、こういうのは総帥が… なんでこんな人殺しみたいなこと言うんだよ！
Commander, this is for the Commander... Why make me sound like a murderer?!
これが圧力だ！
This is peer pressure!
私のこと信じて！お前ら巻き込んでやるからな！
Believe in me! I'm dragging all of you down with me!
行くぞ！押すなよ！押すなよ！
Here I go! Don't push me! Don't push me!
カウントダウン行くぞ！３、２、１、ポチッとな！
Countdown, here we go! 3, 2, 1, press!
うわあああ！
Waaahhh!
動いてる！高すぎる！煙！煙！
It's moving! It's too high! Smoke! Smoke!
何これ？！大丈夫？！高っ！
What is this?! Are you okay?! It's so high!
うわー！すごい！綺麗ー！宇宙だー！
Whoa! Amazing! So pretty! It's space!
ベガの隣にある…どれどれ？あれだあれだ
It's next to Vega... Which one? That one, that one!
すごーい！ここまできたんですね！え、これもこよりが？
Amazing! We came all the way up here! Eh, Koyori made this too?
そうだよ！宇宙ロケットを開発しましたー！
That's right! I developed a space rocket~!
すごーい！ロケットなんだ！初めて役に立ったな！
Amazing! So it's a rocket! You're useful for the first time!
採用してよかった！ 初めてってどういうこと！？
Glad I hired you! What do you mean for the first time?!
毎度毎度怪しいことばっかしてるから… いつもいい物作ってるでしょーが！
Since you're always doing suspicious stuff... I always make good things, don't I?!
本当にちゃんと研究してたんだね。 予算大丈夫かな？
You really were doing research properly. Is the budget okay though?
赤字ですけど…心配しないで！大丈夫大丈夫！
We're in the red, but... don't worry! It's fine, it's fine!
給料無くなる？ 元々無いから大丈夫大丈夫！
Will our salaries be gone? You didn't have any to begin with, so it's fine!
酷いこと言ってるよ！ でも、我々もついに宇宙進出ってことですよね！
That's terrible! But that means we've finally expanded into space, right!
全世界に向けて、我々の新曲を披露するぞ！
To the entire world, let's perform our new song!
おーーーっ！
Ohhhh!
行くぞ！せーの！ 『饗宴ソリダリティ～SHAKE★NABE～』！
Here we go! Ready, set! "Kyouen Solidarity ~SHAKE★NABE~"!
SSholoX... SSholoX...
闇！鍋会！Yummy！鍋回！
Darkness! Hot pot party! Yummy! Hot pot round!
Darkness！Darkness！宴会High！High！
Darkness! Darkness! Banquet High! High!
闇！鍋会！Yummy！鍋回！
Darkness! Hot pot party! Yummy! Hot pot round!
征服！征服！宴会　わいわい！
Conquer! Conquer! Banquetワイワイ (lively fun)!
暗黒な饗宴が今、 (Wah wah wah wah, Wah wah wah)
A dark banquet now, (Wah wah wah wah, Wah wah wah)
始まりを告げ！
proclaims its start!
準備はいいでござるか？
Are you ready?
禁断の蓋を解き放て！
Release the forbidden lid!
迷いの迷宮に　迷い込んだ子らよ
Children who strayed into the labyrinth of hesitation,
ようこそ宵の怪異(かい)へ――
welcome to this strange night...
無礼講！じゃんじゃん！
Forget formalities! Non-stop!
エンジョイな？晩餐会
Enjoy the banquet?
秘密裏に　着火オーライ
In secret, ignition, all right!
夜(よなべ)煮込んだ (鍋だけに☆コツ)
Simmered late into the night (A secret☆trick just for the pot)
O・TA・NO・SHI・MI
Look forward to it!
奉行～！デリシャスだった具材
Hot pot master~! The delicious ingredients,
オーマイガー　禍々しいオーラや
Oh my god, an ominous aura surrounds them!
５人よれば　もんじゅの知恵
When five gather, it's the wisdom of Monju!
追い出汁…ダバダバ…
Extra broth... pouring out...
苦汁も　我らの
Even bitter juices
シュチューにおさめて
become part of our stew,
い・た・だ・き・まーす！ (ハイ！)
Bon appétit! (Hai!)
シェケな鍋イベ！ (ふー！)
Shake that pot event! (Hoo!)
C'mon！エ・ビ・バディバディ♪って！
C'mon! Everybody, buddy♪!
とびっきり　大騒ぎしちゃえ！
Let's make an extraordinary racket!
ぐっつぐつの　ミラクルをつついて
Poking at the simmering miracle,
楽しんだもんが勝ち！おっおー！
whoever has fun wins! Oh-oh-!
Check It！鍋 Event！ (ふー！)
Check it! Pot event! (Hoo!)
わっしょい Gotcha！まぜまぜって！？
Wasshoi, gotcha! Stir it all together?!
ミクスチャー？なんでもありあり？？
A mixture? Anything goes??
あつあつの　スマイルを繋げて
Connecting our piping hot smiles,
世界征服しよー！おっおー！
let's conquer the world! Oh-oh-!
この宴に必要な心得！
The essential rules for this banquet!
一、箸を落とさない！
One: Do not drop your chopsticks!
二、恐れずに食べる！
Two: Eat without fear!
三、楽しむことだー！
Three: Have fun!
「Yes My Dark！！！！」
"Yes, My Dark!!!!"
飢えた皆殿の安心安全を守る
Protecting the peace and safety of everyone starving,
この一刀、旋風の如く食材を刻む
this single blade slices the ingredients like a whirlwind!
はーい！吾輩、食べる担当ー！
Yes! I'm in charge of eating~!
誰でも食べやすい大きさに
Cut to a size anyone can eat easily,
(ジャキン！ジャキン！ジャキン！) お任せあれでござるー！
(Chop! Chop! Chop!) Leave it to me de gozaru~!
Dollar Dollar 鷹の目(アイ)
Dollar Dollar, Hawk Eye,
即・消灯　低予算レシピ
lights out immediately, a low-budget recipe!
不安も不明金も　闇に消してしまおう
Let's make anxieties and unaccounted funds vanish into the darkness!
グラグラ煮えたぎる
Boiling and bubbling,
アク取り、お掃除、合法！
skimming scum, cleaning up, perfectly legal!
バイバイしちゃおーね？
Let's say bye-bye, okay?
組織(ウチ)の団結力(チカラ)を　召・し・上・が・れ！ (ハイ！)
Feast upon the united power of our organization! (Hai!)
シェケな鍋イベ！ (ふー！)
Shake that pot event! (Hoo!)
「こ・こ・か・ら」でーす♡「なにー!?」
...is "right here, right now"♡ "What!?"
実は、こっそり仕掛けをほどこしました！
Actually, I secretly added a little trick!
そろそろ効いてきたかなぁ？
I wonder if it's starting to take effect now?
じゃあ入れた具材を順番に言ってみよ♡
Let's name the ingredients we put in, one by one♡
ナスー――！
Eggplant---!
イクラーーー！
Salmon roe---!
辛―――！
Spicy---!
か、かっこいいー！吾輩もやるー！！
S-So cool! I wanna do it too!!
どやぁ！大成功！
Ta-da! A huge success!
今度はみんなで、いくよー！
Next time, let's do it all together! Here we go!
ナスー――！！
Eggplant---!!
イクラーーー！！
Salmon roe---!!
辛―――！！
Spicy---!!
マヨー――！！
Mayooo---!!
からあげ～～～！！
Fried chicken~~~!!
オムライス～～～！！
Omelet rice~~~!!
ハンバーグ～～～！！
Hamburg steak~~~!!
なんで吾輩だけちがうんだよぉぉぉぉ！！！！
Why am I the only one who's different?!!!!
我らの集大成（キズナ）を示した逸品！
A masterpiece showing the bond of our culmination!
『holoX鍋』が完成★
The "holoX Hot Pot" is complete★
笑顔で囲めば 心がひとつとなる
When gathered with smiles, our hearts become one.
これこそが真の仲間です（ハイ！）
That is what true comrades are! (Yes!)
SHAKE★NABE Event! ハッピーラッキー×ソリダリティ
SHAKE★NABE Event! Happy Lucky × Solidarity
ひとりじゃ 征服できない！
We can't conquer it alone!
わっくわくの スマイルを拡げて
Spreading thrilling, exciting smiles,
この星を統べたいんだ！おっおー！
we wanna rule this planet! Oh-oh-!
Check It! 鍋 Event!（ふー！） ワッチャワチャ ごちゃ混じぇ！で♪
Check It! Hot Pot Event! (Woo!) In a wild, chaotic mix♪
ぷちょへんざっみんなでJoin Join
Put your hands up, everyone Join Join!
あっちあちの バイブスであふれた
Overflowing with scorching-hot vibes,
世界征服 不可能じゃない！
world domination isn't impossible!
せーの！で決めポーズ！おっおー！
On the count of three, strike a pose! Oh-oh-!
闇！鍋会！Yummy！鍋回！
Darkness! Hot pot party! Yummy! Hot pot time!
Darkness! Darkness! 宴会High！High！
Darkness! Darkness! Banquet High! High!
闇！鍋会！Yummy！鍋回！
Darkness! Hot pot party! Yummy! Hot pot time!
征服！征服！ 宴会 わいわい！
Conquer! Conquer! A noisy, lively feast!
(Wah wah wah wah, Wah wah wah)
ああああーーーっ！！
Aaaahhhh!!
あ、あれを見ろーーー！！
L-Look over there---!!
え？ / 何？
Huh? / What?
[ライブかいじょー!!]
[Live Venue!!]
えっ、おい！ / 何だよこれ！ / あれ？ / 砂漠でござるよ！
Wait, hey! / What is this?! / Huh? / It's a desert de gozaru!
我々、宇宙進出じゃないのかー！？
Aren't we supposed to be expanding into space?!
いや、予算の限界です！
No, we've reached our budget limit!
えぇー！？ / 待て待て待て！ / 制作費どこ行っちゃったんだよ！
Eehh?! / Wait, wait, wait! / Where did the production budget go?!
こっちだってめっちゃ練習したんだよ！ / もっとカッコいいの想像してた！
We practiced so hard for this! / I imagined something way cooler!
予算が無いから悪いんだよ！ / 予算無いって何で予算無ぇんだよ！
It's because we have no budget! / Why is there no budget?!
お前らが贅沢するからじゃないかよ！
Isn't it because you guys are being so extravagant?!
予算で遊んでる奴がいるからだろ！
It's because someone's fooling around with the budget!
（口論）
(overlapping bickering)
こんな2周年いやだーーー！！
I don't want a 2nd anniversary like this~~~!!
[holoX 2周年だよ!!!!! この2年間holoXとしても色々あったね...!! まずは5人そろって2周年むかえられて嬉しい♡ みんなも見守ってくれてありがとう♡ 鷹嶺ルイ]
[holoX 2nd Anniversary!!!!! A lot happened over these 2 years...!! First of all, I'm so happy the 5 of us reached our 2nd anniversary together♡ Thank you everyone for watching over us♡ - Takane Lui]
[holoX 2周年 ありがとう!! あっという間に我もJPの先輩や後輩が出来たり、何よりholoXとしての成長の年でした。大変だったけど、嬉しい！holoXerのみんなの応援のおかげだぜ。本当にありがとうございました♡ 大好きだよ♡ 沙花叉クロヱ]
[holoX 2nd Anniversary, Thank you!! In a flash, we got senpais and kouhais in JP, and above all, it was a year of growth for holoX. It was tough, but I'm so glad! It's all thanks to everyone's support. Thank you so much♡ Love you all♡ - Sakamata Chloe]
[holoX 2周年 ありがとう♡ Thank you 個性豊かすぎる5人だけど、だいぶチームワーク上がってきた...かな!? holoXerの皆がワクワクできるように、3年目もっと頑張るよ～♡ これからもよろしくね♡ みんな大好きだっ☆ 博衣こより]
[holoX 2nd Anniversary, Thank you♡ Thank you Although we 5 are uniquely distinct, our teamwork has really improved... right!? I'll work even harder in our 3rd year to keep all holoXers thrilled~♡ Please continue to support us♡ Love you all☆ - Hakui Koyori]
[holoX 2周年だぞ~!!!!! この2年間holoXとしても色々あったね...！ 3年目もholoX・holoXer 一緒に楽しむぞー!! 風真いろは]
[It's holoX's 2nd Anniversary~!!!!! A lot happened with holoX over these 2 years...! In our 3rd year, let's enjoy it together as holoX and holoXers!! - Kazama Iroha]
[祝☆holoX 2周年～!! ラプラス・ダークネス参上 2年目も刮目せよ!! 絶対世界征服!!!!]
[Congrats on holoX's 2nd Anniversary~!! La+ Darknesss has arrived! Keep your eyes on us in year 2 as well!! Absolute World Domination!!!!]
無礼講！じゃんじゃん！ エンジョイな？晩餐会
Anything goes! Bring it on! An enjoyable dinner party?
秘密裏に着火オーライ
Covertly lit, all right!
夜業（よなべ）で煮込んだ
Stewed overnight,
O・TA・NO・SHI・MI
an an-ti-ci-pa-tion!
奉行～！元デリシャスだった具罪
Magistrate~! The sinful ingredients that were once delicious,
おーまいがー 禍々しいオーラ嫌ぁ
Oh my god, an ominous aura, no way!
ハチャメチャだって
Even if it's completely chaotic,
5人よればもんじゅの知恵「えいっ」
five heads are better than one! "Take this!"
追い出汁…ダバダバ…
Extra broth... pouring in...
苦汁も我らの
Putting our bitter juice
シュチューにおさめて
into our stew,
い・た・だ・き・まーす！（ハイ！）
Bon appétit! (Yes!)
[このあとMV公開！ 『饗宴ソリダリティー～SHAKE★NABE～』]
[MV premiere coming up next! "Kyouen Solidarity ~SHAKE★NABE~"]
[近日公開 秘密結社holoX 『饗宴ソリダリティー～SHAKE★NABE～』 リリース記念ボイス]
[Coming Soon: Secret Society holoX "Kyouen Solidarity ~SHAKE★NABE~" Release Commemorative Voice]
[この後 ホロライブ公式チャンネルでMV公開！]
[MV will premiere next on the official Hololive channel!]
この後 ホロライブ公式チャンネルでMV公開！
MV will be released on the official hololive channel right after this!